# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I'm Wang Gang.
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道传统小吃
In this video I will share with you a traditional snack.
# 首先我们准备大米500克放入盆中淘洗干净备用
First, prepare 500 grams of rice and rinse in a bowl.
# 同学们大米可以选择凉糕馒头专用大米
You can choose the special rice that is especially used for rice pudding and Mantou.
# 某宝搜索即有 大约3元1斤
It's available on a Taobao for about RMB 3/jin
# 淘洗干净之后加入适量的清水浸泡24小时备用
After rinsing, add some water and soak for 24 hours.
# 500克的大米发胀之后可以增重到650克左右
500 grams of rice can gain up to about 650 grams after swelling.
# 下一步开始准备石灰粉
Next, prepare the lime powder.
# 准备适量的熟石灰粉（约500克）放入盆中
Prepare some lime powder (about 500 grams) in a bowl
# 然后加入适量的清水化开沉淀备用
Then add the right amount of water to dissolve.
# 同学们石灰粉可以反复使用50次以上
The lime powder can be reused for more than 50 times
# 只需要用清水浸泡沉淀即可使用
Just soak in water to settle and use.
# 且不容易变质
And it doesn't degrade easily.
# 沉淀30分钟之后盛出表面的清水即可
Settle for 30 minutes and then remove the water from the surface.
# 然后将处理好的石灰水下锅开大火烧开
Then put the treated lime water in a wok on high heat
# 大火烧开之后继续沉淀去除底部的石灰
After boiling over high heat, continue settling to remove lime from the bottom.
# 不喜欢碱味的同学可以反复多次的烧开沉淀去除杂质
If you don't like the taste of alkali, you can repeatedly boil the sediment to remove impurities.
# 下一步开始处理米浆
The next step is to start processing the rice milk.
# 首先在料理机中加入适量的大米和清水搅碎备用
First, add some rice and water to a food processor and puree.
# 清水和大米的比例为2:1
The ratio of water to rice is 2:1
# 米浆搅得越细腻凉糕则越嫩
The more finely the rice milk, the more tender the rice cake will be.
# 下一步开始制作
Next, start making the dish.
# 锅中加入烧开沉淀好的石灰水开大火烧开
Boil settled lime water to the wok on high heat
# 然后将处理好的米浆边下边搅拌
Then pour in the treated rice milk while stiring.
# 否则下太快容易起坨不易搅散
If adding the rice milk too quickly, it will form lumps that will not be easily dispersed.
# 直到米浆变得浓稠且烧开两分钟
Until the rice milk thickens and boils for two more minutes.
# 然后把烧开的米浆倒入碗中凉透即可
Then pour the boiled rice milk into a bowl to cool.
# 同学们米浆最好放至自然凉透口感最佳
It would be the best to let the rice milk cool naturally.
# 自然凉透成型大约需要10小时左右（夏天）
It takes about 10 hours to naturally cool and mold (in summer time)
# 下一步开始熬红糖
Next, start preparing brown sugar syrup.
# 准备适量的红糖敲散备用
Prepare a generous amount of brown sugar, and break it up to small pieces.
# 对于凉糕来说红糖有特殊的香味
Brown sugar has a special aroma for rice cakes.
# 其它糖为下品
Other sugars are not as good as the brown sugar.
# 再加入少许的冰糖增加甜度
Add a little crystal sugar to sweeten it up.
# 锅中加入适量的清水之后下入敲好的红糖
Add some water to the wok and then add the brown sugar.
# 再加入少许的食用盐
Add a little more table salt.
# 然后开小火烧开熬化即可
Then turn on the heat and bring them to boil.
# 同学们糖和水的比例为1:1.5
The sugar to water ratio is 1:1.5
# 浓稠度适中
to obtain moderately thickness
# 这个过程不能开大火
You shouldn't turn up the heat on this process.
# 否则熬焦之后会有苦味
Otherwise, it will burn and have a bitter taste.
# 红糖熬化等待冷却之后会变得自然粘稠
After the brown sugar is simmered and allowed to cool, it becomes naturally sticky.
# 凉糕凝固之后可以放入纯净水中再冰镇
Once the rice pudding has set, you can put it in pure water and chill it.
# 吃的时候再取出即可
Just take them out when you want to eat them.
# 最后用小刀将凉糕切成小块
Finally, use a small knife to cut the rice pudding into small pieces.
# 再撒上各自喜欢的水果或者干果
And sprinkle with your favourite fruit or dried fruit.
# 也可以选择芒果 西瓜 山楂 花生碎 芝麻等等
You can also choose mango, watermelon, Chinese hawthorn, peanuts, sesame seeds, etc.
# 最后淋上熬好的红糖浆即可食用
Pour the boiled brown sugar syrup on top and serve.
# 一道夏日消暑甜品红糖凉糕就制作完成
A summertime dessert of brown sugar rice pudding is ready!
# 下面开始技术总结
Let's start the technical summary.
# 第一
First,
# 传统做法采用石磨压米浆
the traditional rice milk is pressed by stone milling.
# 但就口味上来说并无差别
But in terms of taste, there's no difference between the traditional and modern ways of milling.
# 反而机器打磨的效率更高
On the other hand, it is more efficient to use grinding machines.
# 在此推荐机器磨
I recommend machine grinding here.
# 第二
Secondly,
# 凉糕的最佳口感比例为
the optimal ratio for rice pudding is:
# 500克干大米泡发24小时
500g of dried rice soaked for 24 hours,
# 加入两倍的清水磨成米浆
with twice as much water and grind into rice milk
# 磨好的米浆倒入有石灰水3250克的锅中
Pour the ground rice milk into a wok with 3250 g of lime water.
# 同学们米浆和石灰水的比例为3:5（口感最佳）
The best ratio of rice milk to lime water is 3:5 (for best taste)
# 第三
Thirdly,
# 石灰粉最好选择熟石灰
the best choice for lime powder is slaked lime (Calcium hydroxide)
# 生石灰加水容易烫伤人
Lime with water may cause burns.
# 且必须购买食用级的凉糕专用石灰粉
You must purchase food-grade lime powder for use in the rice pudding.
# 红糖凉糕的技术总结完毕
Technical summary of brown sugar rice pudding is complete
# 开始划了哦四伯爷
Start piercing, uncle.
# 要比着这个尺子划
You have to use this ruler.